《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
上膛了吗
Is it loaded?
不上膛的枪有什么意义
Ain't no point in an unloaded gun.
这是柯丽丝汀·柯林格最后几张工资单
It's Kristen Kringle's final paychecks.
她一直没去领  事情不对劲
She never picked them up. I don't like it.
奥斯瓦尔德  你有进展
Oswald, you are making progress.
依据哥谭市的法律
By the laws of Gotham City,
特此宣布你已经精神正常
is hereby declared sane.
你自由了
You are a free man.
想问问你最近有没有柯丽丝汀·柯林格的消息
I was wondering if you'd heard from Kristen Kringle lately.
你觉得她遭遇不测了吗
Do you think that something bad has happened?
我们也不知道她什么时候能醒来
We have no idea when she might wake up.
贱人
Bitch.
想跟我玩是吧  吉姆
So that's the game, is it, Jimbo?
想智胜我吗
Gonna try to outsmart me?
休想
I don't think so.
我们见过吗
We've met before?
是的  你杀了我父母
Yes. You killed my parents.
是谁雇了你
Who hired you?
你永远别想知道那人的名字
You'll never know their name.
我是个禽兽  你得杀了我
I'm a monster. You need to kill me.
你只是个凡人
You're just a man.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
他在里面
He's in there.
"阿尔弗雷德  我要离家一阵
Alfred, I've left home for a while
去街上跟塞琳娜一起生活
to live on the streets with Selina.
相信我  尊重我的意愿
Trust me, and honor my wishes.
别想把我找回来"
Don't try to bring me back.
哥谭艺术博物馆
欢迎光临哥谭艺术博物馆
Welcome to the Gotham Museum of Art.
博物馆每月举办数百项新活动
The museum offers hundreds of new events and programs each month,
包括讲座  演出  巡展
including lectures, performances, tours,
这是个真炸弹
家庭活动等等
family activities and more.
哥谭博物馆的咖啡馆和礼品店位于...
The Gotham Museum Café Gift Shop is located on the...
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence   DustD
翻译 charcie   大K   木浅   小酸奶!   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
继续走
Keep moving.
大家不要惊慌
Okay, folks. Don't panic.
哥谭
第二季  第十五集
一个盗贼约一小时前袭击了博物馆
Solo robber hit the museum about an hour ago.
用一个没爆炸的炸弹把人们吓跑了
Scared people away with a bomb that never went off.
-有人受伤吗  -没有
- Anybody hurt? - Nope.
那叫我们来干吗  不是抢劫组的案子吗
Why us, then? Isn't it a Robbery Squad case?
炸弹威胁归你们
Bomb threats are you guys.
不管炸弹有没有爆炸
Whether the bomb goes off or not.
所以开始调查吧
So get on it.
戈登  你留下
Gordon, you stay.
内务处要重新审阅盖勒文被杀一案的案卷
Internal Affairs is reopening the file on Galavan's murder.
为什么
Why?
匿名线报
Anonymous tip.
有人打电话来  声称看见你
Someone called in, claims they saw you,
那晚在码头杀了盖勒文  而非企鹅
not Penguin, kill Galavan that night at the docks.
内务处每周都会接到一堆骚扰电话
I.A. gets a dozen crank calls a week.
也许只是有人无聊了
Probably just bored.
这个线报提到一个我们没对外公布的细节
This tip came with a detail we didn't put out to the public.
雨伞
The umbrella.
那就是哥谭市警局里有人要找我麻烦
So someone in the GCPD is trying to make trouble for me,
散播谎言  不是没发生过
by spreading lies-- been known to happen.
谎言吗  那你再告诉我一次真相
Lies, huh? Tell me the truth again.
我没杀盖勒文  我当时不在场
I didn't kill Galavan. I wasn't there.
他叫你干什么
What was that all about?
待会儿说
Later.
-戈登警探  -爱德
- Detective Gordon. - Hey, Ed.
-我已经准备好和你谈了  -什么
- I'm ready for our sit-down. - Our what?
你不是想和我谈
You wanted to interview me
柯林格小姐和多尔蒂警官搬走的事吗
about Ms. Kringle leaving town with Officer Dougherty?
没错  抱歉  我们延期吧
Right. Yeah, sorry. Rain check.
我们得去哥谭博物馆
We got to get to Gotham Museum.
艺术品抢劫
Oh, the art heist.
我听说了  真有胆量
Yes, I heard about this. Very bold.
那好  我们延期
Uh, yes, rain check.
加油  朋友们
Tallyho, chaps.
去抓住坏蛋
Go get that bad guy.
我们今天下午再谈
We'll talk later this afternoon.
爱德  不用担心
And Ed? Don't worry.
我会弄清楚柯林格小姐到底怎么了
I'll find out what happened to Ms. Kringle.
我完全相信你的能力  戈登警探
I have the utmost faith in your abilities, Detective Gordon.
相信我
Believe me.
老大  你绝对猜不到谁找上门了
Boss. You'll never guess who just knocked on the door.
既然我猜不到  那为什么不告诉我  蠢蛋
If I'll never guess, then why not just tell me, jackass?
如果你说我可以猜三次
If you say I have three guesses,
那就是个游戏了
well, then that's a game.
尽管是个烦人又愚蠢的游戏  但至少讲得通
It's an annoying and stupid game, but at least it makes sense.
狗娘养...
Son of a...
看看谁来了
Well, well, well.
我听说阿卡姆疯人院放你出来了
I heard they let you out of Arkham.
没错
Yes.
高兴的一天
Happy day.
我正常了
I'm sane.
我有证书
I have a certificate.
但希望我没有打扰到你们
But-But I-I hope I'm not intruding.
我刚刚回到城里
I-I just got back in town, and...
觉得不和老朋友打个招呼就太失礼了
thought it'd be rude not to say hello to an old friend.
老朋友
An old friend?
是啊  我是说...
Well, yes. I mean...
我们的关系起起伏伏
we had our ups and downs,
但整体来看  我觉得我们是朋友
but on the whole, I thought we were friends.
不是吗
Weren't we?
反正我回忆中是这样的
That's what I recall anyhow.
吃小蛋糕吗
Cupcake?
你杀了我哥哥
You killed my brother.
你扰乱他的心智  把他变成了你的奴隶
You messed with his mind and made him your slave.
记得吗
Hello?
我以前是挺坏的  是吧
I guess I was pretty terrible, huh?
我想真心实意道个歉
I want to apologize sincerely.
我之前脑子不正常
I wasn't thinking straight.
我接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
我们杀了他吧
Let's kill him.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
布奇  听着
Uh, Butch, listen.
我已经改过自新了
I've changed.
你没理由害怕我的  我...
You have no reason to fear me. I'm...
我如今是个好人了
I'm a good person now.
我还打算去给你母亲扫墓来着
I was thinking about visiting your mother's grave.
我想念那老太婆了
I miss the old bird.
她的啜泣声晚上总能哄我入睡
Her sobs would often lull me to sleep at night.
奥斯瓦尔德  奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald... Oswald!
救救我
Save me.
那听起来是很像她
That does sound like her.
我觉得他没在骗我们
You know, I think he's for real.
疯人院的那些医生一定是好好整治了他一番
Those loony bin doctors must have done a real number on him.
这还挺让人难过的
It's actually kind of sad.
放他走
Let him go.
什么
What?
你听见我的话了
You heard me.
看他啊  他就是个可悲的废物
Look at him. He's a pathetic loser.
他对谁都不构成威胁
He doesn't pose a threat to anyone.
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
不行  他必须死
No way. He has to die.
这里谁说了算
Who's the boss here?
我相信以眼还眼
I believe in an eye for an eye.
我们都失去了一些东西  他也一样
We've all lost something. Including him.
我们两清了  你和我
We're square, you and me.
-明白了吗  -完全明白
- Understand? - Completely.
好吧
Fine.
我之前还没发现你这么多愁善感呢
You know, I didn't realize you were so sentimental.
不受点惩罚他不能走
He's not leaving without some kind of punishment.
-绝对不行  -好吧
- He's not. - Okay.
你有什么想法
What'd you have in mind?
你内心的小声音在尖叫
Your little private inside voice is screaming.
想告诉我你和巴恩斯的小会谈
Want to tell me what that powwow with Barnes
是关于什么的吗
was all about?
内务处要重启
I.A. is reopening the investigation
西奥·盖勒文被杀的调查
into the murder of Theo Galavan.
有匿名线报
Anonymous person called in,
说看见是我杀了他
saying they saw me kill him.
又是这事啊
That old chestnut, huh?
我能帮你什么吗
Is there something I can do?
你跟你内务处的姐们关系还那么好吗
Are you still friendly with your gal over in I.A.?
金尼吗
Ginny?
我们是有过交集
Our paths have been known to cross.
能尽快再交一次吗
Can they cross again soon?
我得知道他们掌握了什么
I need to know what they have.
好
Sure.
萨奇先生
Mr. Thatch?
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
这位是布洛克警探
This is Detective Bullock.
能跟我们说说那副失窃的油画吗
What can you tell us about the painting that was stolen?
油画题为《灰色疯狂黎明》
The painting is entitled "Mad Grey Dawn"
描绘的是本世纪初的铁路爆炸事件
and depicted a railway explosion at the turn of the century.
较大部分其他藏品来说  并不出众
A minor work compared to much of the collection.
奇怪的是  他毁坏了
Strangely, he simply defaced
画廊另一区内两幅更有价值的画作
two much more valuable paintings in another section of the gallery.
一幅马谢的  一幅拉鲁的
A Marché and a LaRue.
跟我来
Follow me.
简直是物价之宝
Priceless.
什么样的偷画贼会花时间
What kind of art thief would take time
破坏这样的杰作
to defile such masterpieces?
无知的吗
An ignorant one?
不  花了这么多时间和精力
No. This took a lot of time and effort.
他知道自己在做什么
He knows what he's doing.
他对赚钱不感兴趣
He's not interested in profit.
他是想要传达一个信息
He's trying to send a message.
什么信息
Which is what?
不知道
No idea.
那画家呢
What about the painters themselves?
他们怎么了
What about them?
这些问号直接涂在
The question marks are directly over
油画的签名上
their signatures on the canvas.
两人各自有一整本相关传记
There's entire books written on each of them.
-抱歉  -他不会想弄得太复杂
- I'm sorry... -  He would want to keep it simple.
他们的名字呢
What about their names?
马谢是市场的意思
Marché means "Market"
而拉鲁是道路的意思  对吧
and LaRue is "The road," Yes?
-没错  -或者街道
- Yes. - Or "The street."
市场街
Market Street.
他偷走的油画
The painting he stole...
描绘的是铁路爆炸事件对吧
depicted a railway explosion, yes?
没错  就是一桩爆炸案
Yes. A bombing, actually.
被称为血腥星期一
It was known as Bloody Monday.
今天就是星期一
Today is Monday.
联合车站就在市场街
And Union Railway Station is on Market Street.
注意  请大家有序地
Attention, please evacuate the train station
撤离火车站
in an orderly fashion.
请找到离你最近的出口撤离火车站
Please find your nearest exit and evacuate the train station.
-谢谢  -快走
- Thank you. - Move.
-我们要找什么  -不知道
- What are we looking for? - I have no idea.
让大家离开这里  赶快
Get these people out of here! Go! Go!
-赶快离开  -快走
- Get out of here! Go! - Move! Move.
快点
Come on.
-快走  -布洛克
- Move. - Bullock.
大家听好了  炸弹就在储物柜里
Listen up! The device is inside the lockers.
平克尼  赶快疏散人群
Pinkney, get these people out of here.
让他们出去
Get them out of here.
出去  快
Outside, now!
让他们出去  走
Get them out of here. Go!
出去  快
Outside now. Now!
拆弹小队还有多长时间能到
How much time till the bomb squad gets here?
来不及了
Too long.
后退
Get back.
后退  后退  后退
Back, back, back, back.
-走走  -走走走
- Go! Go! - Go! Go! Go! Go!
快走  快走
Go! Go! Go!
叫医护人员来
Get a medic.
你好  艾薇
Hey, Ivy.
你好  小猫
Hey, Cat.
你好  亿万富翁少年
Hey, Billionaire Boy.
他来这里做什么
What is he doing here?
他们就在楼上
They're right upstairs.
他要和我一起待一阵子
He's staying with me for a while
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
艾薇为一个贩卖迷幻蘑菇的帮派工作
Ivy works for a gang that runs the magic mushroom trade.
迷幻蘑菇是什么
What's a magic mushroom?
有些制造幻觉
Some give you visions.
有些使你兴奋
Some give you energy.
有些能帮助你入眠
Some help you to sleep.
我已经栽培出十多种了
I've cultivated over a dozen kinds.
我们来这里做什么
What are we doing here?
这帮派的头头是吉尔兹的侄子  桑尼
The gang is run by Gilzean's nephew, Sonny,
带着他的一帮狐朋狗友
and his merry band of losers.
那么这些蘑菇是违法的
So these mushrooms are illegal.
是的  他们是违法的
Yes. They're illegal.
也就是说这里总会有大量现金
Which means there's always a ton of cash around.
你要抢劫他们
You're going to rob them?
是啊
Yeah.
好  我们要怎么做
Okay. How do we do it?
不是我们
We don't.
你有钱  记得吗
You have money, remember?
多的是呢
A lot of it.
塞琳娜  我说过了
Selina, I told you.
我要靠自己生存
I want to survive on my own.
看看我没了万贯家财
Find out who I am without my money.
卸下布鲁斯·韦恩的光环是谁
Without being Bruce Wayne.
再说  我不介意偷罪犯的钱
Besides, I don't mind stealing if it's from criminals.
计划是什么
What's the plan?
这是裸盖菇
Meet Psilocybe Arkrescens.
也被称作蓝恶魔
Also known as The Blue Devil.
她在帮派今天的午餐里放了几个这玩意
She slipped a few of them in the gang's lunch today,
所以我们现在只要等就好了
so all we have to do now is wait.
-它们有什么效果  -立即致死
- What will they do? - Instant death.
逗你玩的
Kidding.
他们会处于极度放松状态
They'll be in a state of relaxed bliss.
像是在做梦
Like a dream.
相信我  很棒的
Trust me. It's great.
他们还有多久会昏过去
How long until they're out?
一天中从艺术品窃贼变成疯狂炸弹客
From art thief to mad bomber in the same day?
接下来是什么
What the hell is next?
我不知道  但是他想让我们找到的
I don't know, but he wanted us to find it.
我觉得这就是那场抢劫的目的
I think that's what the heist was about.
他在玩一场游戏
He's playing a game.
真好
Great.
哥谭正需要人添乱呢
That's exactly what this city needs.
你找到能表明他下一场行为艺术
Did you find any other brainteasers that might indicate
会在哪举行的脑筋急转弯了吗
his next piece of performance art?
没有  要么他是打算给我们个惊喜
No. Either he's decided to keep it a surprise,
要么就是暂时收手了
or he's taking a break.
我们恐怕没那么幸运
I doubt we're that lucky.
所有空余人手都调来办这个案子
I want every available resource on this thing.
收到
You got it.
打扰  平克尼警官  能在这张
Excuse me, Officer Pinkney, can I get your signature
监管链表上签个名吗
on this chain of custody form?
好
Sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
平克尼
Pinkney.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
我们都合作一年多了  爱德
Been working together for over a year, Ed.
你可以叫我吉姆
You can call me Jim.
吉姆  听说你今天挽救了危局
Jim. Heard you were able to save the day.
幸运而已
I got lucky.
我可不相信运气
I don't believe in luck.
你看出了问题并给解决了  厉害
You saw a problem and you solved it. Bravo.
这次的鉴证你来做
Hey, I want you to oversee forensics on this one.
也许还有好运  能让我们找到
Maybe our luck will hold, and we'll get something
炸弹特征  微量元素什么的
on the bomb's signature or trace elements.
还没有其他线索吗
No other leads yet?
没有  我完全不知道这人想要什么
No, I have no idea what this guy wants
他的目的是什么  这样他就很危险了
or what he's after, which makes him dangerous.
不用担心  有我呢
Well, don't you worry. I'm on the case.
好
Right.
安静
Be quiet.
说不定还有醒着的呢
Someone might still be awake.
你是谁
Who-Who are you?
我们谁都不是
Hey, we're no one.
你在做梦
You're dreaming.
很酷吧
Pretty cool, right?
太酷了
Totally.
好
Yeah.
听着  你要是把咖啡罐给我们
Listen, if you give us the coffee can
然后闭上眼睛  你就能飞了
and close your eyes, you'll be able to fly.
好棒
Sweet.
快跑
Run.
你们要去哪
Where are you going?!
你好啊  小猫
Hey, Cat.
你好  桑尼
Hey, Sonny.
瘦了点嘛
You lose weight?
继续说俏皮话吧  塞琳娜
Keep cracking wise, Selina.
等落到我叔叔手里看你还能笑得出
You ain't gonna be smiling when my uncle gets to you.
看看你那九条命还剩几条
Let's see how many lives you really have left.
企鹅
Penguin.
抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to intrude. I...
我真是狼狈透顶
I'm, um, a bit of a mess.
我正好路过这里
I-I was just passing by and-and...
我能不能...我能进来吗
May I... Could I come in for a moment?
这些羽毛其实没看起来那么暖和
These feathers aren't as warm as they look.
当然  我怎么这么没礼貌
Of course. Where are my manners?
见到你真高兴
It-It's so good to see you.
你最近好吗  老朋友  但愿不错吧
So how have you been, old friend? Well, I hope?
挺好
Yeah. Well.
都挺好  最近挺忙的
I have been. Been busy. I've been really busy.
你呢
And what about you?
听说他们放你出来了
I hear that you've been released.
这...怎么回事
What-- What's... What happened?
就是布奇和塔比莎闹着玩呢
Well, just good ol' Butch and Tabitha having fun.
他们本想杀了我  所以...
They talked about killing me, so...
说起来  他们这样还算好了
this was actually pretty nice of them, considering.
还算好
Pretty nice of them?
看来阿卡姆的人对你的治疗挺有效果
They did a pretty good job on you in Arkham, huh?
我是以朋友的身份  想来告诉你  爱德
I'm here to tell you, Ed, as a friend,
暴力和愤怒解决不了问题
violence and anger are not the answer.
我已经变了  变得更好了
I am a changed man. Better.
你也可以改变
And you can change, too.
不错
Cool.
这建议挺诱人
Tempting offer.
问题是
The thing is...
现在的我正处于最佳状态
the me I am right now is kind of hitting my stride.
我很感激你教我的一切
And I'm really grateful for all that you've taught me,
你告诉我关于吉姆·戈登的丑事
and that bad stuff you told me about Jim Gordon
真的帮了我大忙
is really paying off.
-是吗  -是啊
- Is it? - It is.
帮我想出了最完美的谜语
It's helped me to create the perfect puzzle
以走出我的吉姆·戈登困境
to get rid of my Jim Gordon dilemma.
我本会很愿意跟你说
Normally, I would love to share, but
但说实话  全新的你让我有些不适应
to be honest, the new you is kind of freaking me out.
我真的是在忙
I'm just really busy right now.
我这就走
Well, I'll be on my way.
谢谢你来看我
Thanks for coming by.
我跟内务处的姐们聊了
So, I spoke with my gal in I.A..
告密者说企鹅打盖勒文打到快断气时
The snitch said Penguin was beating Galavan to death
你介入
when you stepped in...
朝他胸部开了一枪
and put a bullet in his chest.
那晚是有别人在场
Someone else was there that night.
要么是有别人  要么就是企鹅告密了
Either that, or Penguin talked.
他才从阿卡姆出来
He did just get out of Arkham--
怎么出来的我无从知道
how the hell he did I'll never know--
但别忘了
but lest we forget,
他是替你背锅才进去的
he was in there for a murder you committed.
是有可能为此记恨你的
A grudge is not beyond the realm of possibility.
他本可以在被捕时说的
He could have talked when he was arrested,
告密以换自由  但他没有
used it to cut a deal, but he didn't.
你内务处的朋友还说别的了吗
Did your I.A. contact give you anything else?
证人同意写声明书
The witness has agreed to swear out a statement.
内务处已正式重启了调查
I.A. has officially reopened the investigation.
你现在是西奥·盖勒文一案的头号嫌犯
You are now the primary suspect in the murder of Theo Galavan.
让我叔叔打给我
Well, tell my uncle to call me!
我知道你以为他会对你心软
Look, I know you think he's got a soft spot for you,
但如果他发现你要打劫他
but I'm pretty sure that's gonna change
他肯定不会心软了
when he finds out you tried to rob him.
我猜  等我告诉他  我就那么大摇大摆地进来
My guess is, he's not gonna be too happy with you either
拿走了他的钱  他对你也不会太满意的
when I tell him that I just waltzed in here and grabbed the cash.
不如放我们走  我们就算扯平了
So, maybe you let us go and we call it even?
那我在这行还怎么混
What kind of message would that send?
不行
No.
吉尔兹家人很看重后果
The Gilzeans are all about consequences.
是看重披萨吧
More like all about pizza.
你试过我们的产品吗  塞琳娜
You ever try our product, Selina?
住手
Stop!
你也太懦夫了吧
Aren't you being rather cowardly?
对女人动手
Assaulting a girl?
对  他说得对
No, he's right.
你说得对  该对男人动手
You know, when you're right, you're right!
住手吧  桑尼  我们明白了
Knock it off, Sonny. You made your point.
你别管这事  塞琳娜
Stay out of this, Selina!
再说我是懦夫
Call me a coward again.
你是个懦夫
You're a coward.
无知  粗野的
An ignorant, brutish...
停手
Stop!
臭小子  躺在地上
While you're down there, kid,
给我舔鞋
lick my boot.
越有劲  越易累
Strength costs wind.
如果你要击倒一个大块头
Now if you're gonna beat a big man,
你只要耗过他
all you have to do is outlast him.
别打了
Stop!
我怎么觉得他喜欢被人揍呢
I actually think he wants a beating.
你是受虐狂吗  小子
Is that your thing, kid?
喜欢疼痛
You like pain?!
无知
An ignorant,
粗野  胆小的跳梁小丑
brutish, cowardly clown.
没错
Yep.
他就是喜欢挨揍
He likes it, all right.
你妈你爸肯定都不正常
Your mom and dad must've been real freaks,
才会养出你这样的怪胎
bringing up a weird kid like you.
够了
Enough!
我们走
Let's go!
走
你好  母亲
Hello, Mother.
这地方真好啊
What a lovely spot.
格特鲁德·卡佩普特
挚爱的母亲
我很抱歉没能来参加葬礼
I'm so sorry I couldn't be here for the funeral.
但我想你一定会以我为傲的
But I think you would be proud of me.
我洗心革面了
I'm a changed man.
至少我在努力做一个好人
Or... at least, I'm trying to be.
说实话
To be honest,
我不知道
I don't know
没有你  我要怎么生活
if I'm gonna make it without you.
你好
Hello?
非常抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
无意打扰
I-I don't mean to interrupt.
没关系
Not at all.
百合
Lillies.
如果我没记错  她最爱百合
Her favorite, if memory serves.
没错
Yes, they were.
你认识她吗
Did you know her?
很久之前认识的
A long time ago.
我又能联系上她时  她已去世了
I found her again only in death, I'm afraid.
我是以利亚·范·达尔
I'm Elijah Van Dahl.
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
Oh, Oswald Cobblepot.
"科波特"
"Cobblepot"?
你是格特鲁德的亲人吗
You're related to Gertrud?
她是我母亲
My mother.
母亲
Mother?
你是格特鲁德的儿子
You're Gertrud's son?
是的
Yes.
抱歉
Uh, I'm sorry.
你究竟怎么认识我母亲的
Uh, how did you know my mother exactly...?
-你多大了  -什么
- How old are you? - Excuse me?
你多大了
How old are you?
-格特鲁德走时  -我31
- Gertrud left... - I'm 31.
31年前  没错
31 years ago, yes.
没错
That's right.
天呐  她...
Oh, my God, she...
她没告诉我啊
she never told me!
告诉你什么
Told you what?
我有个儿子
That I had a son.
炸弹客有消息吗
Any word on the bomber?
布洛克在等鉴证报告
Bullock's waiting on forensics.
真希望我知道他究竟想怎么样
Just wish I knew what his endgame was.
我似乎遗漏了什么
Feels like I'm missing something.
所以你才吃不下去吗
Is that why you're not eating?
是吧
Yeah, I guess.
不是
No.
内务处要重启盖勒文被杀的调查
I.A. is reopening the investigation into Galavan's murder.
为什么
Why?
有目击证人站了出来
An eyewitness came forward.
你跟我说事情都结束了  吉姆
You told me it was over, Jim.
你对我发誓的
You swore to me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我心里就知道还没结束
I knew in my heart that it wasn't,
但我还是让你哄我
but I let you lie to me.
不是的  不是那样
I didn't. I wasn't!
我们早该趁有机会时离开
We should have left when we had the chance.
去个别的地方  更好的地方
Gone somewhere new, somewhere better.
合适养大孩子的地方
Somewhere fit to raise our child!
你知道我不能那么做
You knew I couldn't do that.
我能解决好的
I can fix this.
怎么解决
How?
是你干的
I mean, you did it.
是你杀了盖勒文
You killed Galavan.
我会想到办法的
I'll find a way.
我必须想到
I have to.
如果你做不到呢
What if you can't?
你好  平克尼警官
Hello, Officer Pinkney.
抱歉打搅你休息  我能进去吗
I'm so sorry to bother you at home. Can I come in?
好啊
Uh, sure.
快点说  我看球赛呢
Make it quick. The ball game's on.
什么事
What's this about?
戈登警探会解释的
Oh, Detective Gordon'll explain.
他就来
He's just behind me.
好
Ah, okay.
平克尼
Hey, Pinkney?
黑鸟酒吧叫什么
What do you call a tavern of blackbirds?
撬棒[乌鸦酒吧]
A crow bar.
懂了吗
You get it?
撬棒
A crow bar?
是啊  挺二的
I know, it's kind of lame.
我突然想到的
Just came up with it on the spot.
格特鲁德是作为厨娘来给我父母工作
Gertrud came to work as a cook for my parents.
她那么年轻美丽
She was so young and beautiful.
那么充满活力
So full of life.
那么美丽
So beautiful.
我当时也很年轻
I was young then, too.
还是个孩子
A boy, really.
傻乎乎  浪漫的孩子
A foolish, romantic boy.
我父母发现后
When my parents found out,
他们不许我们在一起
they forbade us from being together.
他们说我是百万财产的继承人
I was the heir to a great fortune, they said.
而她只是个厨娘
And she was just a cook.
我威胁要跟她私奔
I threatened to run away with her.
背弃
Turn my back
我的家族之名  和我的遗产
on my family name and my inheritance.
那是我第一次也是唯一一次抵抗他们
It was the first and only time I ever stood up to them.
他们肯定是知道我不过是说说而已
They must've known my words were just that.
一个惯坏的孩子
A spoiled child
空洞的威胁
making idle threats.
第二天  格特鲁德就走了
The next day, Gertrud was gone.
我父母只跟我说
My parents told me only that
他们达成了协议
they had come to an arrangement.
她会得到照顾
She would be taken care of.
我必须永远不去联络她
And I must never make an attempt to find her.
令我羞耻的是  我真就没去找她
And to my shame, I didn't.
我让他们拆散了我们
I let them separate us.
我完全不知道
I had no idea.
她没有告诉我她怀孕了
She never told me she was pregnant.
她没有跟我提过你
She didn't tell me about you.
如果她说了
If she did...
她跟我说我父亲在我还小的时候死了
She told me that my father had died when I was still a baby.
大概是比真相好接受吧
Easier than the truth, I suppose.
你父亲是个懦夫
That your father was a coward
不愿抵抗父母
who wouldn't stand up to his parents.
她肯定是觉得
She must've figured
你俩自己生活能过得更好
that the two of you would be better off making your own way.
这大概也是事实
Which, in fact, was probably the truth.
看看你
Look at you.
是多么坚强的年轻人
A strong young man.
她把你养得很好  是吧
She did a good job, didn't she?
她尽力了
She tried.
我们都很想她
We both miss her terribly.
我可怜的儿子
My poor boy.
你一直在这世上孤身一人
You've been all alone in the world.
是啊
Yes, I have.
今后不会了
No longer.
你有家了
You have a home.
有父亲了
And a father.
有家庭了
And a family.
家庭
"A family"?
快乐的大家庭
A big, happy family.
他们见到你会很高兴的
They're going to be so thrilled to meet you!
先生
S-Sir, please?
请老实告诉我
Tell me truthfully.
这是梦吗
Is this a dream?
不是梦  孩子
It's not a dream, my boy.
你回家了
You're home.
喂
Yeah.
鉴证结果刚出来
Forensics just landed.
炸弹的定时器是
The timer on the bomb was activated
手机遥控启动的  这很聪明
remotely by phone, which was smart.
这样他有机会提前放置炸弹
Gave him time to plant it in advance
再在自己想的时候启动
and set it off when he wanted.
有号码吗
We get a number?
有
Yeah.
电话是用西杜威大道17号内一部付费电话打的
Call came from a pay phone inside 17 West Dewy Avenue.
离联合车站只有几个街区
Just a few blocks from Union Station.
付费电话啊
Pay phone, huh?
好  我过去看看
All right, I'll go over there and check it out.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
他现在大概早走了
He's probably long gone by now.
我反正也睡不着
I can't sleep anyhow.
嗯
Yeah.
有人吗
Hello?
平克尼
Pinkney.
戈登
Gordon?
你来这儿做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
放下枪  快点
Put your gun down. Now!
把枪放在地上
Place your gun on the floor,
我不会说第二遍了
I won't say it again.
好
Okay.
听我说
Listen to me.
我只是在跟进一条炸弹客调查的线索
I was just following up a lead on the bomber investigation.
你跟进线索跟到平克尼的公寓来了吗
You were following up a lead in Pinkney's apartment?
不是
No.
我不知道平克尼住在这里
I didn't know that this was Pinkney's apartment building.
你为什么来这儿
Why are you here?
平克尼给我发了短信
Pinkney sent me a message.
说想私下谈谈
Wanted to talk outside of work.
谈什么
About what?
你
You.
我得带你回警局
I have to take you down to the precinct.
这是个误会
There's been a mistake.
希望如此  孩子
I hope so, son.
希望如此
I hope so.
就好了
Almost done.
从没见过谁那么能挨打
Never seen someone take a beating like that before.
我觉得桑尼说得对
I think Sonny is right.
你是喜欢疼
You do like pain.
我挨打的时候
When it was happening...
就好像其他一切都不存在了
...it was like nothing else existed.
一直以来让我纠结的一切
Everything I've been struggling with,
空虚
emptiness...
迷惑
...and confusion...
都消失了
It just vanished.
很久以来
And for the first time...
我第一次
in a long time,
确信自己不会有事
I knew I was going to be okay.
我知道不管桑尼把我怎么样
I knew that whatever Sonny did to me...
我都能承受得住
...I could take it.
他无法击垮我
That he couldn't break me.
没人可以
That no one can.
没人是坚不可摧的  布鲁斯
Nobody's unbreakable, Bruce.
需要叫工会代表来吗
You want your rep here?
这不是我干的  有人陷害了我
I didn't do this. Somebody set me up.
死因
Cause of death:
头部受钝器重击
blunt force trauma to the head.
警监  听我说
Captain, listen to me.
凶器是一根撬棒
Murder weapon was a crowbar.
我们在沙发下发现的
We found it under the couch.
上面有你的指纹
Your fingerprints were on it.
在联合车站  我用一根撬棒打开了储物柜
At Union Station, I used a crowbar to open up the locker.
肯定是有人给拿走了
Somebody must have picked it up.
那人又恰巧知道
And that someone just happened to know
你今晚会去找平克尼警官吗
that you'd be paying Officer Pinkney a visit tonight?
我说了  我并不知道他住在那里
I told you, I didn't know that he lived there.
鉴证组查到炸弹客的电话
Forensics traced the bomber's call
是用楼内一部付费电话打的
to a pay phone in the building.
布洛克能证实我的说法
Bullock will back me up.
他是证实了
He did.
但我管他要报告时
But when I asked for the report,
上面却没有提到遥控计时器
it had nothing to do with a remote timer
或追踪电话
or any traced call.
我知道这看上去不妙
I know how this looks.
但平克尼是我们自己人
But Pinkney was one of us--
我为什么要杀他
why would I kill him?
因为他正是指认了你的匿名线报
Because he was the anonymous witness that fingered you.
我们在
We found this
平克尼家找到了
Internal Affairs form
这份内务处表格
at Pinkney's place.
这与匿名线报者的
It's the exact same statement
陈述一模一样
that the anonymous witness made,
但平克尼在这份上签了名
only Pinkney signed this with his own name.
他大概是不敢
I guess he got cold feet
公开检举你
about putting himself on the line.
于是改用了匿名线报的方式
So he sent in the anonymous tip instead.
哥谭警局目击者证词
一定是觉得你会下狠手
Must have figured you'd get nasty.
我不知道你是怎么知道的
I don't know how you figured it out,
但你发现了他就是证人
but you found out he was the witness.
不是
No.
或许你去他家  想劝他别那么做
Maybe you went over to his place to talk him out of it?
我说了  我不知道他住那里
I told you I didn't know it was his place.
或许你根本没打算跟他谈
Or maybe you had no intention of talking
你就是去杀他的
and you just killed him.
你了解我
You know me.
我知道你和盖勒文
I know that something went down
那晚上出了什么事
between you and Galavan that night.
内务处审你的时候  我从你眼神中看出来了
I saw it in your eyes when I.A. was grilling you.
而现在唯一
And now the one person
要揭露这一切的人
who was about to shine light on this whole thing
被人打死  你还站在他尸体旁
is found beaten to death with you standing over the body.
我遗漏了什么吗
What am I missing?!
-我被人陷害了  -吉姆
- I was set up! - Jim!
你听过多少
How many lying,
撒谎的渣滓混蛋
son of a bitch, low-life weasels
用过同样的说辞
have you heard use that same line?
有人陷害你
Somebody set you up?
你就找这么个借口
That's what you're going with?
你至少也该承认自己做了什么
The least you could do is admit what you did.
像个爷们样
Be a man!
平克尼是我们的一员
Pinkney was one of us.
他理应得到真相
He deserves that.
我也该得到真相
I deserve that!
你至少也该看着我的眼睛
The least you could do is look me in the eye
让我记起你还曾是个好警察
and remind me that you were a good cop once.
你依然知道是非对错
That you still know right from wrong.
吉姆
Jim.
我想找工会代表
I want to talk to my rep.
你有辱警徽
You're a disgrace to the badge.
我信任你
I trusted you!
但你伤了我的心
But you broke my heart.
你
You,
带他去郡监狱
take him to county.
我不要他待在这里
I don't want him here.
吉姆
Jim.
哈维
Harvey.
炸弹客  哈维
The bomber, Harvey.
今天发生的一切都是为了设计我
Everything that happened today was set up to trap me.
炸弹客  哈维
The bomber, Harvey!
戈登警探为期四周的
The four-week murder trial of Detective Gordon
凶杀审判刚刚结束
concluded just minutes ago
陪审团一致判定有罪
with the jury returning a unanimous verdict of guilty.
法官判罚最高刑罚
The judge handed down the maximum sentence
他将在黑门监狱服刑40年
of 40 years to be served at Blackgate Penitentiary.
陪审团经过不到24小时的
The jury was unanimous in its decision
审议便得出了一致裁决
after deliberating less than 24 hours.
地检官哈维·丹特
District Attorney Harvey Dent
尚未作出评论
was not available for comment.
整个审判期间
...throughout the trial,
由于不利证据...
based on the overwhelming evidence against...
你没事吧
You okay?
这不对
This isn't right.
这不可能
This can't be right.
有什么事对吗
Tell me something that is.
阿卡姆疯人院
几小时前
Just hours ago,
詹姆斯·戈登警探的凶杀审判结束了
the murder trial of Detective James Gordon concluded
陪审团达成了一致的
with the jury returning a unanimous verdict
有罪判决
of guilty.
法官判罚了最高刑罚
The judge handed down the maximum sentence
他将在黑门监狱服刑40年
of 40 years to be served at Blackgate Penitentiary.
陪审团
The jury
达成了一致判决
was unanimous in its decision...
天呐
Oh, my!
终于醒了
Awake at last.
地检官哈维·丹特
District Attorney Harvey Dent
尚未作出评论
was unavailable for comment.
你好啊  亲爱的
Well, hello, dear.
谁去叫斯特兰奇教授
Someone call Professor Strange.
我们要上诉
We're gonna fight this.
-小莱  -你听到了吗
- Lee. - Did you hear me?
不惜一切  我们一定要上诉
No matter what it takes, we're gonna fight this.
证据不会改变
The evidence isn't gonna change.
你是无辜的
You're innocent.
我远远不是无辜的
I'm far from innocent.
我们都清楚
We both know that.
怎么  那我们这就放弃吗
So, what, we just give up?
我们向前看
We move on.
向前看
Move on?
什么意思
Move on to what?
你是指我
You mean... me.
你是指我得向前看
You mean I move on.
-我认真地考虑很久了  -不
- I've thought long and hard about this. - No.
你得听我的
You have to listen to me.
我听够了
I'm tired of listening.
这不公平
This isn't fair!
你怎么能不陪在我们身边
How can you not be with us?
生日
Birthdays...
第一步
and first steps
擦破膝盖
and skinned knees...
一切
and everything.
难道要隔着铁栏相见
What, what, visits through bars
不知道哪天半夜会
and-and not knowing when the phone is gonna ring
接到电话  得知你...
in the middle of the night to tell me when you're...
我不希望那样
I don't want that
我不要你们那么生活
for either of you.
-你还有机会得到幸福  -不
- You still have a chance at happiness. - No.
你得去别的地方
You need to go somewhere.
远离这里
Far away from here.
找个好地方养大我们的孩子
Somewhere fit to raise our child.
开始新生活
Start a new life.
忘记我
Forget I exist.
只有这样我们才能挺过来
It's the only way either one of us survives this.
不  吉姆
No, Jim!
别再联络我了
Don't try to contact me again.
我不会回应的
I won't reply.
不
No.
别这样
Don't do this.
对不起  小莱
I'm sorry, Lee.
吉姆  别这样  我爱你
Jim, don't do this! I love you!
真对不起
I'm so, so sorry.
吉姆
Jim!
敬酒
A toast.
我想感谢你们的宽容
I want to thank you all for your generosity.
你们敞开怀抱和心胸接纳了
You have welcomed Oswald into our family
奥斯瓦尔德进入我们的家庭
with open arms and open hearts.
为此  我深感幸运
And for that, I am truly blessed.
敬家庭
To family.
你们让我
Uh, you guys have made me
成了这世上最幸福的人
the happiest man on the planet.
我真的好感激
I am so grateful.
我爱你们每个人
I love you all.
家庭
Family.
敬家庭
To family.
-哥哥  -是  是
- Brother. - Yes! Yes.
是啊
Yes.
囚犯戈登  转狱
Inmate Gordon, prison transfer!
打开大门
Open gate.
黑门监狱
我会查明是谁陷害了你
I'm gonna find who set you up.
这事没完
This ain't over.
嗯
Yeah.
这段时间以来你是个好搭档  哈维
You were a good partner, Harvey.
我现在也是
I still am.